Guide to the Major Attractions Committee records, 1957-1995 UA.09.13.0006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Major Attractions Committee records
1957-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Union. Major Attractions Committee
UA.09.13.0006
6 Linear Feet
Major Attractions is a committee of Duke University Union. Its purpose is to present major events of contemporary entertainment with an emphasis on popular music. The collection contains files about attractions and artists brought to the Duke Campus by the Major Attraction committee. Materials present include administrative documents including annual reports, budgets, and policy notices, correspondence, committee minutes, performance contracts, hospitality/technical riders, publicity materials, and clippings. Dates in the collection range from 1957-1995.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Major Attractions Committee records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973-2007.
Historical Note
Major Attractions is a committee of Duke University Union. Its purpose is to present major events of contemporary entertainment with an emphasis on popular music, as well as other events the committee proposes all the while striving to present a diversity of programs to the university community. The committee is administered by students and consists of General membership and an Executive Committee made up of the following positions: chairperson; publicity chairperson; security/usher chairperson; hospitality chairperson; and finance chairperson.
Duke University Union was founded in 1954, as the Duke Student Union, with the purpose of promoting the social, recreational, cultural, educational, and spiritual activities of the students. The Union consists of the following committees and programs: ACE (All Campus Events); Broadway at Duke; Cable13; the Coffeehouse; Freewater Presentations; Freewater Productions, Major Attractions; Major Speakers; Small Town Records; Visual Arts; and WXDU.
Collection Overview
The collection contains files about attractions and artists brought to the Duke Campus by the Major Attraction committee of Duke University Union. Materials present include administrative documents including annual reports, budgets, and policy notices, correspondence, committee minutes, performance contracts, hospitality/technical riders, publicity materials, and clippings. Not all attractions and artists actually came to or performed on campus on the dates indicated; some folders may contain information on proposed events that did not occur. The collection is arranged into the following groupings subject files, publicity, and performances. Dates in the collection range from 1957-1995.
Separated Material
Concert posters were removed and placed in the Poster Collection.
Related Material
Duke University Union records, 1951-
University Archives. Duke University.
Major Speakers Committee records
University Archives, Duke University.
Popular music; Mass media and publicity; Clippings (information artifacts); Duke University. Union. Major Attractions Committee; Duke University -- Joe College Weekend; Duke University. Union
- Subject files
  - Administrative Stuff, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Booking (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - CEA Negotiations, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - Committee Heads, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Concession Report, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1991, (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - Fees for Contracts, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Finances, 1987-1990 (Box 1)
  - Form letters, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - General, (3 folders), 1970-1971; 1978; 1983-1985 (Box 1)
  - Hospitality, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Joe College
    - Southern Folk Cultural Revival Project, April 3, 1971 (Box 1)
    - David Frye, April 22, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Fuzzy Mountain Boys, April 23, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Major Attractions Committee, 1957-1978, (6 folders) (also contains information concerning Joe College) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1971; 1987-1993 (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Policy Proposal II,, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Press kits, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Program Council minutes, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Program Council and Combined Programming Council and Executive Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Roll Books, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Semester reports and events evaluation, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Student Union Committee minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Summer Executive Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Southeast Regional N.E.C Conference, Charleston, SC, October 3-5 (Box 1)
  - Telegrams, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Whisper Concerts, correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Southern Folk Cultural Revival Project, April 3, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Concert Proposals, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Weldon, Williams, and Lick, Inc. Ticket Orders, 1965-1969 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
- Publicity
  - Bios, Photos, Flier Originals, 1991-1992 (the Sklar Days) (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - BoDeans (Box 1)
  - The Connells (Box 1)
  - Mike Cross (Box 1)
  - The Cure (Box 1)
  - Dreams So Real (Box 1)
  - Driniv 'n' Crazy, Oktoberfest (Box 1)
  - Bob Dylan (Box 1)
  - Earth, Wind, and Fire with the Emotions, Fall 1976 (Box 1)
  - Fine Young Cannibals (Box 1)
  - Indigo Girls (Box 1)
  - Jorma Kaukonen (Box 1)
  - Bob Mould, Ultra Vivid Scene (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Royal Crescent Mob, Oktoberfest (Box 1)
  - Various artists, undated (Box 1)
  - Various Artists, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - The Veldt (Box 1)
  - Lionel Hampton, 1983 Nov. 19 (Box 5)
  - Joni Mitchell, 1974 Mar. 24 (Box 5)
  - Grover Washington, Jr. with Patti LaBelle, 1978 Apr. 18 (Box 5)
  - Beach Boys, 1981 Oct. 25 (Box 5)
  - Aretha Franklin, 1969 Apr. 26 (Box 5)
  - Beach Boys, Grateful Dead, Bread, Butterfied Blues, 1971 Apr. 24 (Box 5)
- Performances
  - The Young Rascals, September 29, 1967 (Box 2)
  - The Play of Daniel, November 29, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Lookaway Club: Raun McKinnon, December 4-9, 1967 (Box 2)
  - The Turtles, September 28, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Simon and Garfunkel, October 12, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Sam and Dave Revue, November 23, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Beatles, "Magical Mystery Tour," February 15, 1969 (Box 2)
  - James Cotton Blues Band, March 1, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Janis Joplin, March 1, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Aretha Franklin, April 26, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Dionne Warwick, April 27, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Mitch Ryder, March 9, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York Rock and Roll Ensemblr, May 15, 1969 (Box 2)
  - The 5th Dimensions Corp., October 4, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Dionne Warwick, November 22, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Dreams, March 14-15, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Sly and the Family Stones, March 14, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Blood, Sweat, and Tears, April 24, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Moody Blues and Dion, September 26, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Green Lyte Sunday, October 1970 (Box 2)
  - The Guess Who, October 1970 (Box 2)
  - Poco, November 21, 1970 (Box 2)
  - The Byrds, November 21, 1970 (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Howdy Doody - "Buffalo Bob," December 1970 (Box 2)
  - Mountain and Mylon, February 13, 1971 (Box 2)
  - James Taylor, February 12, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Jeremy Storch, March 1971 (Box 2)
  - Jackson Browne, March 1971 (Box 2)
  - Laura Nyra, November 21, 1970 and March 6, 1971 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Grateful Dead, Beach Boys, Mountain, Butterfield, April 1971 (Box 2)
  - Canned Heat, September 18, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Blues Project, September 18, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Mandrill, October 1971 (Box 2)
  - Traffic and Fairport Convention, October 1971 (Box 2)
  - Leon Russell (The Shelter People), 1971 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Livingston Taylor, October 1 1971 (Box 2)
  - Bread, October 1, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Sha Na Na, October 30, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Ten Years After, November 20, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Yes, November 1971 (Box 2)
  - Peter, Paul, and Mary, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Edgar Winter's White Trash and J. Geils Band, January 1972 (Box 2)
  - SweatHog, January 1972 (Box 2)
  - Isaac Hayes "Hot, Buttered Soul," February 1972 (Box 2)
  - Allman Brothers Band with Alex Taylor, February 5, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Batdorf and Rodney, September 1972 (Box 2)
  - Jackson Browne, September 1972 (Box 2)
  - Jackson Browne and Batdorf and Rodney, September 1972 (Box 2)
  - Grateful Dead (proposal), September 1972 (Box 2)
  - Eagles and Mahavishno Orch, September 1972 (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Van Morrison, October 1972 (Box 2)
  - The Persuasions, Stevie Wonder, October 1972 (Box 2)
  - Stevie Wonder, October 1972 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Poco, October 21, 1972 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Osibisa, October 1972 (Box 2)
  - YES, November 11, 1972 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Tranquility, November 1972 (Box 2)
  - Tammy Wynette, February 10, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Tammy Wynette and George Jones,, February 1973 (Box 2)
  - Alex Haley, February 1973 (Box 2)
  - Frank Zappa/Mothers of Invention, February 24, 1973 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Kenny Loggins Band with Jim Messina, March 1973 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Rod Stewart and the Faces, September 19, 1973 (Box 2)
  - New Riders of the Purple Sage, Commander Cody and his Lost Planet Airmen, October 20, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Dave Mason, November 2, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Crosby and Nash, November 15, 1973 (Box 2)
  - The Grateful Dead, December 8, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Bonnie Raitt, January 18, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Seals and Croft, February 17, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Joni Mitchell, March 1974 (Box 2)
  - Gregg Allman, March 17, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Dean Scott Show, August 31, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Jefferson Starship, October 29, 1974 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Dicky Betts and SHF, November 1974 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Earth, Wind, and Fire, November 1974 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - The Dobbie Brothers, December 1974 (Box 2)
  - Larry Gatlin, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Les McCann, January 1975 (Box 3)
  - Bruce Springsteen, Cancellation, February 1975 (Box 3)
  - Marshall Tucker Band, March 7, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Jesse Colin Young/Leo Kottke, April 1975 (Box 3)
  - Kenny Loggins Band with Jim Messina, September 1975 (Box 3)
  - Roberta Flack/Richard Pryor, September 1975 (Box 3)
  - Frank Zappa, October 1975 (Box 3)
  - Allman Brothers, November 1975 (Box 3)
  - Bruce Springsteen, March 28, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Jerry Garcia, April 1976 (Box 3)
  - Grateful Dead, September 1976 (Box 3)
  - Earth, Wind, and Fire, November 12, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Boston, February 13, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Boston (ticket sales), February 13, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Santana, March 18, 1977 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jimmy Buffet, October 1977 (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Karla Bonoff, December 7, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Atlanta Rhythm Section and Sea Level, January 1978 (Box 3)
  - Grover Washington, April 1978 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Grateful Dead, April 12, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Kenny Loggins, October 1978 (Box 3)
  - Jimmy Cliff, November 1978 (Box 3)
  - Bob Marley and De Wailers, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Down Under, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Roy Ayers, October 1979 (Box 3)
  - The Mike Cotter Band, October 12, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Bonnie Raitt, November 15, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Pat Metheny, December 4, 1979 (Box 3)
  - John Prine, March 5, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Pousette Dart Band and Liv Taylor, April 1980 (Box 3)
  - The Dixie Dregs, April 25, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Steve Forbert, October 24, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Sea Level, November 7, 1980 (Box 3)
  - The Cars, November 22, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Tim Weisberg, December 10, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Bruce Springstein, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Marshall Tucker, January 25, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Jimmy Buffet, February 22, 1981 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jazz Concert - Duke Gardens, March 1981 (Box 3)
  - Chick Corea and Gary Burton, March 27, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Dave Crosby, April 23, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Peter Tosh, July 31, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Mike Cross, September 18, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Dave Bromberg, October 16, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Beach Boys, October 25, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Jorma Kaukonen, March 4, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Grateful Dead information [crowd control], 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - The Grateful Dead, September 23, 1982 (Box 3)
  - The Psychedelic Furs, January 20, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Tommy Dorsey, September 1, 1983 (Box 3)
  - McEnroe/Vilas, September 16, 1983 (Box 3)
  - The Volunteers, September 17, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Neil Young Solo Tour, September 28, 1983(3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Lionel Hampton, November 18, 1983 (Box 3)
  - The Kinks, November 30, 1983 (Box 3)
  - The Police, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Mike Cross, February 10, 1984 (Box 3)
  - The Producers, April 7, 1984(2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Billy Idol, September 6, 1984 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - R.E.M., September 25, 1984 (Box 3)
  - The Psychedelic Furs, October 10, 1984 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Cyndi Lauper, November 2, 1984 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Mike Cross, February 12, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Marshall Crenshaw, Springfest, 1985(2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Eric Clapton, April 18, 1985(2 folders) (Box 4)
  - UB40, October 16, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Paul Young, November 5, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Hooters, December 5, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Elvis Costello/Branford Marsalis, October 10, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Love and Rockets, November 16, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Echo and the Bunnymen, February 20, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Mike Cross, April 17, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Springfest, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Bruce Hornsby, September 30, 1988 (Box 4)
  - UB40, October 4, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Windham Hill, November 15, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Springfest, April 14, 1989 (Box 4)
  - The Cure, September 20, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Fine Young Cannibals, September 27, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Oktoberfest, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Blues Traveler, December 2, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Bob Dylan, November 8, 1989 (Box 4)
  - The Indigo Girls, January 21, 1990 (Box 4)
  - BoDeans, February 17, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Ani Difranco, March 1, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Springfest, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Nikki Meets the Hibachi, June 8, 1990 (Box 4)
  - The Veldt, September 1, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Oktoberfest, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Murray Attaway, October 22, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Bob Mould/Ultra Vivid Scene, October 31, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Springfest, 1991/Pre-Exam Jam, April 20, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Dillion Fence, September 19, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Spin Doctors and Lucy Brown, October 21, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Roger Manning, November 25, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Blues Traveler, December 11, 1991 (Box 4)
  - NYC Showcase, April 3, 1992featuring Soul Craft and Cecil Baxter (Box 4)
  - Springfest, April 10, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Luka Bloom, April 21, 1992 (Box 4)
  - They Might Be Giants, September 22, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Cracker with Walt Mink, October 27, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Dillion Fence, November 6, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Toad the Wet Sprocket, November 11, 1992 (Box 4)
  - 10, 000 Maniacs, November 15, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Big Head Todd and Monsters, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Homecoming, 1993 (Box 4)
  - The Goats, January 24, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Soul Asylum, March 16, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Springfest, April 16, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Sun 60, September 17, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Widespread Panic, September 29, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Oktoberfest, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Smashing Pumpkins, November 14, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Homecoming, 1994 (Box 4)
  - The Samples, February 13, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Beck, March 26, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Greg Osby, April 8, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Jeru and Black Moon, December 4, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Juliana Hatfield, Breakeven concert #1, September 6, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Oktoberfest, September 15, 1995 (involves discussions of open concert attendance policy) (Box 4)